Steven Charles Huang [Web Developer]

(917) 617-3306 steven.charles.huang@gmail.com

www.stevencharleshuang.com www.linkedin.com/in/stevencharleshuang github.com/stevencharleshuang

Full-stack web developer with a passion for making game applications in unconventional ways. Recent successful graduate of the Web Development Immersive program at General Assembly with up-to-date knowledge of JavaScript, Node, Express, React and Databases using PostgreSQL. First-hand experience in data-structuring and database feed errors while working with an E-retailer selling on various E-commerce platforms including Amazon, Ebay, and more. Detail-oriented and collaborative, with the ability and drive to deliver projects against strict timelines and standards.

Experience

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive

March 2018 - June 2018 New York, NY

Engineering Fellow

- During a 12-week intensive course, learned JavaScript, jQuery, version control through Git using Bash CLI and building full-stack web applications using React, Node, Express, PostgreSQL and Ruby On Rails
- Conceived, planned and executed four projects with self-determined daily schedules to meet hard deadlines, three of which were web apps requiring full-stack development
- Collaborated with other developers to create a full-CRUD web application that utilized data from Google's Places API
- Collaborated with UX students on a three-hour "hackathon" project. Planned, prepared and delivered an investment pitch for a web app that provided a platform for General Assembly alumni to stay connected with each other and directly collaborate with one another on projects

Layla Girl Ltd.

E-Commerce Specialist

June 2012 - March 2018 Staten Island, NY

- Created product listings for eBay, Amazon, Walmart and company websites
- Uploaded and maintained inventory of product listings using Magento, HTML, and CSV files
- Monitor product feed to ensure successful transmissions
- Troubleshoot any resulting feed issues specific to each E-Commerce marketplace
- Reviewed and resolved any issues involving cataloging and product descriptions
- Copy editing for product descriptions

Ming Yuan After School

Instructor

September 2009 - June 2013 Brooklyn, NY

- Managed groups of 15 to 20 fifth grade students to complete daily homework assignments and larger projects providing assistance as needed and feedback on completed work
- Promoted confidence on a personal level for each student to solve problems accurately and efficiently with increasing independence
- Planned and provided additional assignments to be completed after daily homework assignments
- Maintained discipline of students while providing an encouraging and positive learning environment

Skills

HTML 5 Git PostgreSQL

CSS 3 Rails Ruby JavaScript Crafty.js Bulma Node Canvas Bash

Express WebSockets

React JSON Web Tokens

Adobe

Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Premiere, InDesign

Languages

Fluent in Taiwanese and basic French

Education

General Assembly June 2018 Web Development Immersive Engineering Fellow

SUNY Purchase College May 2009

Conservatory of Music Bachelor of Music Studio Composition

• Dean's List • Cumulative GPA: 3.49

Interest

Leadership

Worship Ministry Leader at Taiwan Union Christian Church 2010-2012

Audio Software

Pro Tools, Adobe Audition, Sibelius, Reason

Produced, recorded, mixed, mastered

Yeti "Shadowhead" (2014)

Yeti "Pill" (2015)

Mastering Engineer

Giga Herbs "Mad Weird" (2014)

Giga Herbs "Mad Deep" (2016)

Giga Herbs "Mad Love" (2018)